# **Gautham Arasu**

thi.gautham@outlook.com | (469) 432-5281 | linkedin.com/in/th-gautham\_l th-gautham.github.io

BC		

Professional Interests Data science, machine learning research, deep learning, statistics and data

visualization.

Technical Skills Python (TensorFlow, Scikit-Learn, Pandas, Numpy, Scipy etc.), RStudio, Jupyter

Notebook, MATLAB, git and others. Experienced in data visualization libraries such as ggplot2, pyplot, seaborn and others. Engineering modelling and simulations in CATIA V5, ANSYS, IcePak and others. Familiar with AWS, Talend and Salesforce. Experienced in Agile, Functional data analysis and Process design and development.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **PUBLICIS SAPIENT**, Associate Technology

San Francisco, CA (Jan 2020 – Present)

- Develop data-driven insights to identify process design improvements; collaborate with stakeholders to scale development and develop predictive models to inform business decisions to senior management.
- Wrangle data from multiple sources (open gov data orgs and systems) using Python and R to manipulate large datasets for insights and leveraged ETL tool such as Talend to setup data governance and data cleansing process
- Built a new approach to commercial valuation, where assessment increased from 9.1% to as high as 14.7% in June 2020.

#### ASTA CRS, Consultant

San Francisco, CA (Jan 2019 – Jan 2020)

- Served as Functional Lead to project delivery team with the responsibility of business process ownership for solution implementation and collaboration multi-competency teams of data engineers, solution architects and business analysts.
- Educating project stakeholders and Public Sector SME's into Agile methodology

EMNSPC Lab, Graduate Research Assistant

Arlington, TX (Jun 2016-Nov 2018)

Amazon, Product Analyst

Bangalore, IN (Dec 2015-May2016)

# **EDUCATION**

Master of Science, Mechanical Engineering, University of Texas at Arlington Bachelor of Science, Mechanical Engineering, Visvesvaraya Technological University

Arlington, TX (May 2018)

Bangalore, IN (July 2015)

#### PERSONAL ACCOMPLISHMENTS & PROJECTS

-"Object detection in building plans for Valuation assessment" – Implemented a CNN segmentation POC on building plans to the Deputy Assessor Office as part of Public Sector DBT Implementation.

-"Sales Insight on residential and commercial property" – Built a valuation assessment model leveraging predictive analysis and presented solution to Public sector clients.

- -"Certified ScrumMaster (CSM)", Scrum Alliance.
- -"Outstanding Teamwork & Publics Service Award" Global Project Delivery Team, Assessor Property Assessment System Team.
- -Thirunavakkarasu.G and et all, "Air flow pattern and path flow simulation of airborne particulate contaminants in Cold aisle containment high density data center using air-side economization"; DOI: 10.1115/IPACK2018-8436;

San Francisco, CA (June 2020)

San Francisco (Apr 2020)

Mountain View, CA (Jan 2020) San Francisco, CA (Dec 2019)

San Francisco, CA (Aug 2018)